荷兰的犹太人不再被允许踏入公园散步
DUTCH JEWS ARE NO LONGER ALLOWED
TO WALK IN PARKS
也不许进餐馆和公立学校
OR GO TO RESTAURANTS
OR STATE SCHOOLS.
被剥夺自由,被种族隔离，
绝大多数人接受了他们的命运
DEPRIVED OF THEIR FREEDOM AND
SEGREGATED, MOST ACCEPT THEIR FATE
希望这种耻辱是能发生的最坏的事
IN THE HOPE THAT THE HUMILIATION
IS THE WORST THAT WILL HAPPEN.
泰兹勒，我希望周一开始，在正午以前
Tazelaar, I want it started up
by Monday, before noon.
维护可以在C13实施
Maintenance can be carried out on C13.
Den Daas.
那些文书已经分类了
谢谢你
That transfer has been sorted out.
Thank you.
不要忘了医生的嘱托
好的
Don't forget the doctor's note.
OK.
一切顺利！
Have a nice day.
苏斯坎德先生？
Mr Silskind?
主管想要见你
The director would like to see you.
不能等到周一吗
Can't it wait till Monday?
爸爸！爸爸！
Daddy! Daddy!
是谁的生日呀?
我的
Whose birthday is it?
Mine.
你看起来真可爱
You look so pretty.
好的孩子们，穿上外套
OK kids, coats on.
Paul, Saar, Anne, Lou.
你有点迟到了
You're a bit late.
她是你的女儿
She is your daughter, you know.
谁要去厕所？
Who needs the toilet?
快点
好的
Hurry up.
Yeah.
我原本也应该呆在德国的。
是的，但你现在在阿姆斯特丹。
I might as well have stayed in Germany.
Yes, but you're in Amsterdam now.
但是要待多久呢？这全部的一切
走向何方呢？
But for how long
and where's it all leading?
去礼堂(剧院)。
你正开车带孩子们去那儿，现在
To the theatre.
And you're driving the kids there, now.
没开车？
Without a car?
是的
Yeah...
那么我们步行吧
Then we'll walk.
我因为那些杂碎而离开，
那个臭名昭著的国家
I leave that stinking country
because of that bastard
他在尾随我
狗娘养的
and he follows me!
The son of a bitch.
掐掉了你的工作
真卑鄙
To pinch your job,
how mean!
沃尔特，如果那是发生的最坏的情况
Walter, if that's
the worst thing that happens...
大家都在吗？
来，亲爱的
ls everyone here?
Come on, sweetheart.
犹太人
JEWS ONLY
来，孩子们
Come on, kids.
你拿到了吗？
是的，拿回给Dark Ages
Have you got it with you?
Yes, back to the Dark Ages.
Silskind一家
The Silskind family.
7个人
Seven people.
你来一个吗？赛亚？
保罗
Do you want one, Saartje?
Paul.
威登希尔，克里斯安？
是的
Vreugdenhil, Christiaan?
Yes.
你也在演出现场吗？
我是钢琴师
Are you in the show too?
I'm the pianist.
犹太人？
不。
Jewish?
No.
跟我来
怎么了？我不是犹太人
Come with me.
What's going on? I'm not Jewish.
长官，你不能那么对待艾瑞斯
Officer, you can't treat
Aryans like that.
你在这儿干什么？
What are you doing here?
我在这儿看滑稽剧。
让他弹钢琴。
I'm here for the revue.
Let him play the piano.
跟你们有什么关系？
What business is it of yours?
作为一个德国人，我一直为穿制服的
德国人而骄傲，就像你
As a German, I'm always proud
of Germans in uniform, like you.
绝对正确
Always correct.
请拿纸。
Papers, please.
给你
Here you are.
Mr Silskind?
Yes.
请稍等
Wait here.
Mister...
先生
不错的材料
A nice piece of rough.
如果你想出售，我老板有办法
If you want to sell it,
my boss will know what to do with it.
你还在工作？
You still have a job?
你没被解雇吗？
我运气不错
You didn't get fired?
I got lucky.
你不必去德国了？
我可以呆在阿姆斯特丹。
You don't have to go to Germany?
I can stay in Amsterdam.
我拿到了一个SPERRE证
别管我为什么
I've got a Sperre.
Don't ask me why.
这不是德国佬那里来的。
不是，来自犹太人理事会
It's not from the Krauts.
No, the Jewish Council.
把你的白布条，分类一下。
你能找个那样的吗？
Get your white rag, sorted.
Can you get one just like that?
哦，不是那样的...
Well, not just like that...
你可能得为他们工作
你在担心什么呢？
You probably have to work for them.
What are you worrying about?
如果你能在阿姆斯特丹谋生
If you can earn a living,
here in Amsterdam
在这儿骑你的自行车，在这儿自由呼吸
在阿姆斯特丹
and ride your bike here and breathe
the air here, in Amsterdam...
你自己擦屁股好了关我什么事呢
You can wipe your arse
with that rag for all I care.
至少我不必去酸菜佬的地方
At least I don't have to go
to Krautland.
西蒙，来
Simon, come on.
你在这儿干什么呢
你家住哪儿啊？
What are you doing here,
where do you live?
你坐在这等谁呢
What are you sitting there for?
过来，你要把我逼疯了
我的鞋子里有个石头
Come here, you're driving me crazy.
There was a stone in my shoe.
当心！警察！
Watch out, a cop!
请出示证件
我住在这儿
Papers, please.
I live here.
鲁斯，鲁斯，来这儿。
Roos! Roos, come here!
逃走，鲁斯。
闭嘴
Go away, Roos.
Shut up!
滚开，你个肮脏的犹太人
Go away, you stinking Jew!
爸爸
Daddy!
战争会结束的，会有那一天的
Some day the war will end.
然后，她将去上学
她会活下来
And then she will go to school,
and she will live
她还会结婚
and she will get married.
我们会成为爷爷和奶奶
And we will be
a grandpa and grandma.
你会是个伟大的爷爷
You'll make a great grandpa.
汉娜，你愿意答应我一件事吗？
Hanna,
will you promise me something?
你愿意永远和我在一起吗
Will you stay with me always?
无论发生任何事
Whatever happens?
犹太人理事会
JEWISH COUNCIL
劳驾，劳驾
EXCUSE me, EXCUSE me.
劳驾，劳驾，劳驾
EXCUSE me, EXCUSE me, EXCUSE me.
早上好
Good morning.
你已经来了，珀拉克先生.
会占用一小会时间，请跟我来
You're already here, Mr Polak.
It may take a while, but follow me.
谢谢
Thank you.
坦白说，我从没自己来过某个德国工厂
To be honest, I don't see myself
in some German factory.
当然你将被免除检查，
只要你是这里不可或缺的人
You'll be exempted, surely.
As long as you're indispensable here.
你，我...
我现在在哪儿?
You, me...
Now, where was I?
哦,吐根医生和他的家人
他们可以被排除
Ah, Dr.Tugendhafi and his family,
they can be removed.
医生真地是不可或缺
Doctors really are indispensable.
我们很幸运绅士们可以有权选择驱逐谁
We're lucky the gentlemen are allowed
to choose who has to be deported.
不是德国人?
不是
Not the Germans?
No.
他们只是说一个数量
我们自由决定是谁
They just say how many.
We're free to choose who.
设想一下报传票的情形
Imagine getting
a summons to report.
你不能报,他们会来抓你
You could not report in.
Then they'll come and get you.
艾尔小姐,是我搞错了还是这里有新来的人
Miss Elzas, am I mistaken
or is that someone new?
那是珀拉克先生,来自理事会
他来这整理名单
That's Mr Polak from the Expo.
He is here for the lists.
啊,名单
Ah, the lists!
猜猜我们已经从名单上排除多少个了
Guess how many we've managed
to remove from the list.
布莱姆,或许珀拉克先生不喜欢猜谜语
Bram, perhaps Mr Polak
doesn't like riddles?
14000,他们全有Sperre证。
谁也料不到吧?
14,000, all of them a Sperre.
Who would have thought?
实话说,你料到了吗?珀拉克先生?
Did you expect that, Mr Polak?
Be honest.
没有,我以为最多是10000或者12000
No. Ten, maybe.
Twelve, at the most.
今天上午,我们跟党卫军喝咖啡了
This morning,
we had coffee with the SS.
我必须得说,咖啡棒极了
Excellent coffee,
I must say.
突然,那个费尔长官先生问...
Suddenly, that Mr Aus der Filnten asks...
Hauptsturmï¬‚lhrer Aus der Filnten.
他问理事会要多少人
He asks how many people
the Council needs
一年之内装上火车
to get everyone on the train
within a year.
那是他说的话.
我说20000
That's what he says.
I say twenty thousand.
在商言商,你要求20000,实际能得到14000
Once a businessman always a businessman
You ask for 20, you get 14.
像老鼠一样,艾斯先生.
我们像阴沟里的爬鼠一样.
Like rats, Mr Asscher.
We're walking into the trap like rats.
科奇先生,这真的是唯一的办法
Mr Kisch,
this really is the only way.
这真是堕落
我们要成为纳粹的帮凶吗
A slippery slope.
Do we want to become the Nazis' slaves?
我们有使命在身
接受现实吧
Is that our mission?
Adapting.
我们因为接受现实已经苟活了2000年
We've survived
for 2,000 years by adapting.
这会是上帝最后的诅咒
This could, God forbid,
be the last time.
请坐,科奇先生
坐下?
Please sit down, Mr Kisch.
Sit down?
你的名字在那儿吗?珀拉克先生?
Is your name on there, Mr Polak?
苏斯坎德是我的名字.沃尔特.苏斯坎德
Silskind is my name, Walter Silskind.
Sluzker.
你想要被排除,我理解
And you would like to be removed?
I understand.
但是我恐怕不能帮你,抱歉
But I'm afraid I can't help you.
Sorry.
听着,你应该知道我有相当重要的工作经验
Listen, you should know
I have considerable work experience.
装载1000乘客的船已经裂缝
A ship with 1,000 passengers
has sprung a leak
救生艇只有能搭载50人的空间
and there is only room
for 50 in the lifeboat.
其余的950人怎么办?
What about the other 950?
他们就该死吗?
They're just allowed to perish?
我从38就在霍格文的克虏伯家族工作
I worked at Krupp.
And since '38 at Hoogovens.
你要明白,一周之内我在此不可或缺
You'll see, I'll be indispensable here
within a week.
作为一个钢琴师?
As a pianist?
我也会踢踏舞.
我是个公司经理,很称职
I can tap dance too.
I'm a company manager, a good one.
荷兰礼堂(剧院)
DUTCH THEATRE
157,694张卡片
157,694 cards.
德语.
复式簿记
The German way.
Double-entry bookkeeping.
这是一张名单上每个人名的卡片
There's a card
for every name on the list.
Watertight.
Felix.
Felix Halverstad.
After the war he'll be an artist again.
战后,他将重新做一个艺术家.
他们等着被拉去西波克集中营
They wait here for transportation
to Westerbork camp.
他们不能直达吗?
一次性去140000人?
Can't they go straight there?
140,000 people on a train in one go?
你一周发送两次
You send them twice a week,
一次400或500人
400 or 500 people at a time.
这儿是厕所
Here is the toilet.
一个厕所?你知道一个家庭一天的排泄物得多少吗?
One toilet? Do you know how much
waste matter a family produces in a day?
400或500个家庭
这里没有家庭和孩子
Times 400 or 500 families...
No families or children here.
德国人不想听抱怨
The Germans don't like whining.
你让他们在哪儿?
那儿.
Where do you keep them then?
There.
在犹太教会堂?
那是收留儿童的地方.
In the synagogue?
That's where the children are housed.
扔掉经书,你已经变成一个
Get rid of the Torah
and you've got a créche.
党卫军相当机警
The SS are certainly resourceful.
所以把孩子隔离了
So the children are separated
from the parents upon arrival?
带来这儿,是的
堕落.
And brought here, yes.
The slippery slope.
你仍然还可以拒绝这个职务
并归还袖章
You can still refuse the position
and return the armband.
我们会在这儿见到你.
你的孩子在这儿.
We'll see you here anyway.
Your child here.
你和你的妻子站在前排穿过街道.
让我们知道.
You across the street with your wife
in the front row stalls. Let me know.
那么做想干什么?
What do you want with that?
逃跑,藏匿
To escape. Hide.
你已经疯了吗?如果他们抓住我们,
他们会送我们去毛特豪森
Have you gone mad? If they catch us,
they'll send us to Mauthausen.
那是你想要的吗?你的女儿在集中营?
藏匿是禁止的
Is that what you want? Your daughter
in a prison camp? Hiding is forbidden!
沃尔特,我为你骄傲.
我们得到了一个Sperre证
Walter, I'm so proud of you.
We've got a Sperre.
是的，如果我接受作为纳粹傀儡的工作
Yes, if I take that job
as the Nazi's stooge.
如果你不接受，会有10，20，,100个别的人做。
If you don't, there'll be ten others
who will. Twenty, a hundred.
一定有人做.
为什么?
Someone has to do it.
Why?
为什么我们必须离开?
我们是守法的荷兰公民.
Why must we leave?
We're ordinary Dutch citizens.
或许你可以诉诸于女王,只要她关心
几个犹太人的话
Maybe you can petition the Queen.
As if she cares about a few Jews.
你知道你不做这个工作会发生什么吗?
Do you know what will happen
if you don't take that job?
警察!
解散!
Police!
Get lost!
从后面出来
Out the back!
来,快跑
Come on, run!
从那儿上来
Up there!
鲁斯
Roos.
Simon, grab my hand.
抓住我的手
开着我.走
来
Look at me. Let go.
Come on.
呆在你那儿!
西蒙,往前走,鲁斯,跟他呆一起
Stay where you are!
Simon, go on. Roos, stay with him.
妈妈!
Mummy!
快跑！快跑！
Run! Run!
早上好。
今晚在家吃吗？
Good morning.
Will you be eating at home this evening?
不了，谢谢
No. Thank you.
半瞎，没下巴
Half-blind. Lower-jaw gone.
你还是个人吗？
你说的什么话？
Are you still a human being then?
What are you talking about?
海姆特。我的哥哥
Helmut. My brother.
前排右边？
是的。
The Eastern Front?
Yes.
他被授予一等十字勋章
He was awarded
the Iron Cross First Class.
一个英雄
是的
A hero.
Yes.
非常不同于这里的那些给我们的荣誉抹黑的人
Quite different from those here who are
dragging our honor through the mud.
去中央局？
To the Central Bureau?
然后去礼堂(剧院)
是的，先生！
And then on to the theatre.
Yes, sir!
我们的任务是什么？我们怎么处理这个任务？
What were our orders? How were we going
to take care of this task?
你记得吗？
Do you remember?
哦？
Well?
快，排队
Quickly, orderly, thoroughly.
怎么？洛特纳？
How? Rottenï¬‚lhrer?
Tectonically, Herr Sturmbannï¬‚lhrer.
也许事情对你来说还没明朗，但是我们毕竟不是救援军
It may not have dawned on you yet
but we're not the Salvation Army.
当家大人，是日耳曼人吗？
Beating people up in the street,
is that Teutonic?
长官不应该问责他的部下吗？
An officer shouldn't berate his men.
当他们打死手无寸铁的人时？
Even when they're beating
helpless people to death?
人？
腐败的标志。
People?
Symptoms of decay.
我再一次警告你
I'm warning you, once more
你快要变成你哥哥的样子了
and you'll be going
where your brother went.
我们在此一起面对把这个任务顺利完成
Together we face the task
of making things run smoothly here.
预防更坏的情况发生
And prevent worse happening.
我们全都知道该提防什么人和什么事
We all know who and what
we have to be on the alert for.
忍受他们
你也如此
Tolerate them like you would a storm.
You can't do much about that either.
Yachting!
有了纪律和努力，
我们就能完成光荣的任务。
With discipline and hard work,
we can fulfill our honorable task.
豪普，我可以把你介绍给苏斯坎德先生吗？
Hauptsturmï¬‚lhrer, may I introduce you
to Mr Walter Silskind?
他被理事会指派来此负责
He has been appointed
by the Council to take charge here.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen.
你们必须高效率地献身于执行此项工作。
You must execute your tasks here
with efficiency and dedication.
这是张贴在此的规则。
规则一:日耳曼政治骚乱将被严惩不贷
There are certain rules to be adhered
to. Rule number one: Teutonic regime.
Disorder will be severely punished.
规则二：不容许哭泣或其他情绪化行为
Rule number two: Tears or other displays
of emotion will not be tolerated.
规则三：将采取强硬措施反对为家人
和朋友骗取特权的行为
Rule number three: Tough action
will be taken against all attempts
to fraudulently obtain privileges
for family or friends.
每个人要有贯彻执行此项工作的意识。
此项工作10个月内结束。
It is in everyone's interest
that this operation
proceeds flawlessly
and is concluded within ten months.
希尔希特勒
Heil Hitler!
你要来那样子报告吗？
Would you come and report like that?
如此逆来顺受？
So meekly and obediently?
说起来容易，
人们很恐惧。
That's easy for you to say,
people are scared.
他们原本应该烧掉登记表
They should have burned the registers.
然而，他们只是把表递给了酸菜佬：
“这里，150000个犹太人”
Instead they just hand them
to the Krauts. "Here, 150,000 Jews."
在德国工作...
Working in Germany...
我是个被上帝诅咒的波兰异教徒,
I'm a godforsaken Polish pagan,
比什么都不是强,
穆斯林...
Won'h less than nothing,
the Muselmann...
他们踢我这儿,
他们踢我哪儿.
They kick me hen-2,
they kick me there.
斯古耶?
多可爱的名字呀!
Schoontje Schelvis?
What a lovely name!
他叫什么?
布莱姆.
And what's his name?
Bram.
去苦力营?
To a labourcamp?
他甚至走不了路!
He can't even walk yet!
首先换个干净尿布,
然后睡一觉?
A clean nappy first,
and then a sleep?
长官，够了，停止吧
Sir. That's enough now, stop.
你已经登记了吗？我能看看你的传票吗？
Have you registered yet?
Can I see your summons?
长官，请停止。
Sir, please stop.
听着，够了。
Listen, that's enough.
长官?
Sir?
我想你停止。不，不。
I want you to stop. No, no.
你必须这么做吗？
Do you have to?
让我走，你个杂碎！
我可以拿你的钥匙吗？
Let me go, you bastard!
May I have your keys?
冷静点，冷静点。
什么？
Calm down, calm down.
What?
怎么回事？
沃特曼夫人，我可以拿你的钥匙吗？
What happened?
Mrs Waterman, may I have your keys?
你的钥匙
Your keys.
这个就是
你单独一个人吗?
That's it.
Are you alone?
夫人，你是单独一人吗？
有丈夫吗？有孩子吗？
Madam, are you alone?
Husband? Children?
违纪记录
Disciplinary case.
你不说荷兰语吗？
比你说的好，你个肮脏的酸菜佬
Don't you speak Dutch?
Better than you, you filthy Kraut!
可能去藏起来了
Probably went into hiding.
比例减半并立即驱逐
Rations halved
and immediate deportation.
我得出去
听着，我的孩子们...
I have to get out of here
Listen, my children...
我的孩子!
My children!
我们已经变得十分日耳曼化了.
是的.
We're getting quite Teutonic already.
Yes.
那真正的意思是什么?
某些事情非常德国化
What does that really mean?
Something very German.
是的,战争
Yes, war.
有了你这样的人,
你就不必反犹太人了
With people like you,
you don't even have to be anti-Semitic.
我该为你祈祷吗?
已经迷失了.我从不祈祷.
Shall I pray with you?
Get lost. I don't pray, ever.
那么,你不是犹太人?
哦,那么我为什么在这儿?
So you're not Jewish?
Oh, so why am I here then?
没人知道.
No-one knows.
我能问你件事吗?
那是唱的什么歌?
Can I ask you something?
What's there to sing about?
你有更好的主意了吗?
Have you got a better idea?
Nice catch.
他吃好了吗?
是的.
Did he eat well?
Yes.
到入睡时间了.
Time to have a sleep.
再见,妈妈
Bye, Mummy.
他是我的.
当然,他是.
He's mine.
Of course he is.
你可以一天来喂他两次,
但是现在你得离开.
You can come and feed him twice a day,
but now you have to go.
不,我想让他呆在身边
No! I want to keep him with me.
拦住她,拦住她.
Stop her. Stop her.
斯古,听着.
Schoontje, listen.
不,他们要带走我的孩子.
No, they're taking my child away!
冷静点,很快你就能在一列火车上把布莱姆
抱在怀里了.我保证.
Calm down. Soon you'll be on the train
with Bram in your arms. I promise.
好吗?我保证
OK? I promise.
我保证.
来吧.
I promise.
Come on.
苏斯坎德先生?
什么事?
Mr Silskind?
What?
你知道他们要去哪儿吗?
Do you know where they're going?
西波克.
是的,之后呢?
Westerbork.
Yes, but after that?
在德国做工
To work in Germany.
还有呢?
What? What else?
不知道.但是这很令人厌恶.
No idea. But it stinks.
你得让我走.
夫人.
You have to let me go.
Madam.
我的孩子们正在街上流浪.
请离开.
My children are wandering the streets.
Please, leave.
停下.
Stop it.
停下,停下!
Stop it, stop it!
就这样留下他们吗?
他们应该在CRAOCHE.
And just leave them?
They should be in the créche.
去他的吧.你要送你的孩子去德国做工吗?
Créche, my arse! Are you sending
your kids to Germany to work?
你知道他们多大吗?
Do you have any idea how old they are?
妈妈?
Mum?
妈妈？
Mummy?
为什么她不在这儿？
Why isn't she here?
Please knock in future.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
你打算埋葬我吗？
Are you going to grass on me?
白痴
Idiot.
复式簿记
Double-entry bookkeeping.
违纪记录也标记在卡片上了。
The disciplinary cases
are marked on the cards too.
我知道。这只是工作的一半
I know. This is only half of the work.
哦，你希望我也来扮演英雄吗？
Oh, you want me to play the hero too?
你拿到了钥匙。
去文件室的。
You've got the key.
To the file room.
Felix...
为什么你要接受这个烦人的差事？
Why did you take this lousy job?
像你一样...
为了救自己.
Like you...
to save my skin.
是的.那是你能够就得了的
Yes. And that's all you can save.
沃尔特.
Walter.
你认为我不恐惧吗?
Do you think I'm not afraid?
你原本不该变成一个犹太人.
You shouldn't have become a Jew then.
你在干嘛?她在屋顶上!
谁?
What are you doing? She's on the roof!
Who?
我想让他回来!
I want him back!
我想让我的孩子现在就回来!
I want my child back now!
布莱姆!
Bram!
让她从屋顶上下来.快点.
Get her down off the roof. Quickly.
穆勒!让她从那儿下来,
什么办法都行.
Muller! Get her down from there,
using any means.
布莱姆!布莱姆!
Bram! Bram!
你似乎还没明白.
规则一?
You don't seem to have understood me.
Rule one?
我想...
规则一?
I tried...
Rule one?
日耳曼政权,
霍尔
Teutonic regime,
Herr Hauptsturmï¬‚lhrer.
我绝不容许骚乱.
Under no circumstances
will I tolerate chaos.
这是个意外.
我怎么阻止呢?
It was an accident.
How could I stop it?
你的教堂,你的责任
Your theatre, your responsibility.
为什么？
Why?
他们做错了什么？
What have they done wrong?
他们存在就是错
They exist.
真可怕。
I'm scared.
那就是他们想要的
That's exactly what they want.
这种仇恨来自何方?
Where did such hatred come from?
因为我们本身?
不.
Because of what we are?
No.
因为他们对我们的臆断.
Because of what they think we are.
因为我们所教授他们的东西
Because of what we teach them.
纯洁和猥琐
About the pure and impure.
有一条分界线
That there is a dividing line
在接受和不能接受之间
between what is acceptable
and what is unacceptable.
我的床
My bed!
你是谁?
那是我的床!
Who are you?
That's my bed!
那是你的床吗?
Is that your bed?
你知道吗?
来,过来.
You know what?
Come and get it, come on.
不要.
过来.
Don't.
Come on.
西蒙!
Simon!
来这儿,你.
让我走!
Come here, you.
Let me go!
放他走!
Let him go!
不,不要
杂碎!
No, don't!
Bastard!
你在干什么,
你个犹太小贱人?
What are you doing,
you little Jewish bitch?
这是今晚的驱逐资料吗?
This is the deportation material
for tonight?
412人.
我们必须增加数字.
412 people.
We'll have to increase that.
翻一倍,乘以10!
你有足够的工人吗?
Double it, multiply it by ten!
Do you have enough workers?
当然,我有一个好团队.
Absolutely, I have a fine team.
谢谢你.
Thank you.
豪普,我可以问你件事吗?
Hauptsturmï¬‚lhrer,
may I ask you something?
说.
Go ahead.
他们去哪儿?
Where do they go?
我是说,到西波克之后?
I mean, after Westerbork?
我的责任火车一开就结束了.
这是我仅能告诉你的.
My responsibility ends when the train
leaves. That's all I can tell you.
犹太人欠我们劳力,
我们自己的人正在打仗.
The Jews owe us their labour,
while our own men are fighting the war.
那么德国将使得犹太人感激最终的胜利?
So Germany will have the Jews
to thank for its eventual victory?
豪普,
我发现一个纰漏,一个D
Hauptsturmï¬‚lhrer,
I have found a discrepancy, a 'D'.
一条驱逐记录,卡片上有,名单上没有.
A disciplinary case, which is
on the card but not on the list.
逮捕他们.他们全体.
Arrest them. All of them!
是的.长官!
Yes, sir!
处死犹太人!处死犹太人!
Death to Jews! Death to Jews!
你们一起关到毛特豪森.
Off to Mauthausen with the lot of you.
知道你们突然记起名字.
Unless you suddenly remember the name.
谁篡改了名单?
Who messed with the list?
霍尔,我保证我绝不容许破坏和篡改.
Herr Hauptsturmfiihrer, I assure you I do
not tolerate sabotage or falsification.
但是这或许是个笔误.
我们毕竟是人不是神.
But it might be a mistake,
we're only human.
胡说八道.
That's bullshit.
给我个说得通的理由不惩罚你们的笔误。
Give me one good reason
why I shouldn't punish your 'mistake'.
苏斯坎德先生...
Mr Silskind...
我会得到什么?
What would I achieve?
命令
Order.
没有我,你选择了骚乱.
Without me, you choose chaos.
因为我从机器上挪了个小齿吗?
Because I remove one small cog
from the machine?
你的机器将继续运转.
我很容替换
Your machine will go on working.
I'm easy to replace.
但是有一个区别
But there is one difference.
你可以相信我,
我是德国人.
You can trust me.
I'm German.
什么意思?
我是一个商人
Meaning?
I'm a businessman.
一个识时务的人
A realist.
所以我采取了识时务的做法
So I take a realistic approach.
我接受的德国修养,上的德国学校.
I've had a German upbringing,
went to a German school.
我把你当做上级
I acknowledge you as my superior.
霍尔,让我做我的工作.
Herr Hauptsturmï¬‚lhrer,
let me do my job.
苏斯坎德先生?
我们很清楚.
Mr Silskind?
Just so we're clear.
再笔误一次,你就上火车.
One more 'mistake'
and you'll be on the train.
连同你的家人.
With your family.
上帝,我以为我要死了.
My God, I thought I was going to die.
我得到了公正的对待.
I was treated correctly.
他可能喜欢我.
一个党卫军人?
He probably likes me.
An SS man?
或许,他对我信以为真.
Maybe he's fallen for me.
但是,怎么回事?
哦,没什么.那个傲慢的白痴!
But what happened?
Oh, nothing. That arrogant idiot!
海佛先生,傻瓜.大英雄用他的墨水来反对一伙
恶棍
Mr Haiverstad. The dimwit. The big hero
with his ink against a gang of crooks.
冷静点.一切会完美了结.
好.
Calm down. It all ended well.
Yeah.
那边有人病了.去看看.
There's someone ill back there
over on the side. Go and see.
392, 393, 394.
395, 396, 397.
请勿动手.
Keep your hands off me.
跟我们来!
人渣!
Come with us!
Scumbag!
看!
Look!
妈妈,妈妈!
Mummy! Mummy!
鲁斯!西蒙!
Roos! Simon!
我说安静点.
I said be quiet.
西蒙!放我走!
Simon! Let me go!
你聋了吗?安静点!
放我走.西蒙!
Are you deaf? Be quiet!
Let go of me. Simon!
闻起来不错.
That smells good.
我是沃尔特叔叔.
I'm Uncle Walter.
你呢?
And you?
我是鲁斯,那是西蒙.
嗨,西蒙.
I'm Roos and that's Simon.
Hi Simon.
没有证件,什么也没有.
他们呆在这儿行吗?
No papers, nothing.
Is it alright if they stay here?
怎么回事?
那是来自普世的恶霸.
What happened?
It was that bully from Puls.
关键人物.
你得在这儿睡.
The key man.
You'll just have to sleep here.
关键人物这儿不允许.
Key men aren't allowed in here.
晚安
Goodnight.
沃尔特叔叔?
Uncle Walter?
他们带妈妈去哪儿?
Where are they taking Mummy?
我想要谢谢你.
I wanted to thank you.
谢什么?
What for?
没埋葬我.
For not grassing on me.
我想要道歉。
And I want to apologise.
我是个白痴。
是的.
I'm an idiot.
Yes.
干你的活吧.
Just do your job.
是的长官.
另一只手.
Yes, sir!
Other hand.
让他们腐烂
Let them perish.
我们在救生艇上是安全的.
亲爱的.
We're safe in the lifeboat.
Darling.
如果我能救得了他们之中的一个.
If I could just have saved one of them.
我们需要藏起来吗?
知道一切结束.
Are we going into hiding then?
Until it's allover.
没有人剩下.我能听到上帝责怪我.
And there's no-one left.
I can hear God berating me.
你的话是什么意思?
不能接受.
What do you mean?
That it's unacceptable
在纯洁和猥琐之间存在着差别
that a distinction is made
between pure and impure.
不要试图成为英雄,沃尔特.
Don't try to be a hero, Walter.
我以后将怎么跟她解释我除掉了100,000人?
How am I going to explain to her later
that I got rid of 100,000 people?
上帝知道他们在哪儿结束.
And God knows
where they end up.
我们呢?
What about us?
没有人能帮我们吗?
Is there nobody who can help us?
上帝?
God?
我们不得不自助自救
没有上帝.
We'll have to manage on our own.
Without God.
但是我有你.
But I've got you.
是吗?
Haven't I?
做你该做的
Do what you have to do.
皮耶特.
沃尔特.
Piet.
Walter.
你能来太好了.
对.
Glad you came.
Right.
考尔,我有另外一个.
Cor, I'll have another one.
我在听着.
I'm listening.
没有豪言,没有暴力,没有武器.
从没有.也没有那些孩子
No heroics, no violence, no weapons.
Never. Not with those kids.
那些索引卡的问题遗留着.
The problem of
those index cards remains.
是的,我们知道所有的这些事情
Yes, we know all about that.
但是锁链牢固取决于最弱的一环.
But a chain is only as strong as
its weakest link.
费尔长官.
无耻,笨蛋.
Aus der Filnten.
Unscrupulous, a lout.
或许是个杂碎.但是极端的孤独.
A bastard maybe. But as lonely as hell.
你问什么认为他好喝酒?
Why do you think he drinks?
他们全都很孤独吗？
They're all lonely?
为什么你认为我仍然在这儿？
Why do you think I'm still here?
我跟他说话的时候像一个酸菜佬跟另一个说一样。
I talk to him as one Kraut to another.
他每次都让我有机会
He gives me every opportunity
说服他相信如果他不让我留下
他就是个混蛋
to convince him he's an arsehole
if he doesn't let me stay.
听着
Listen...
我可以把这个换成白兰地和雪茄吗
Can I exchange this
for brandy and cigars?
好东西，
不是低劣货。
Good stuff,
not that rotgut.
问问老科尔
Ask Old Cor.
军士是个好警官。
他们的确是。
The sergeant is a good cop.
They do exist.
你要白兰地干什么？
安慰，安抚，庆祝。
What'll you do with the brandy?
Soothe, conciliate, placate, win over.
费尔长官.
这是带我们去哪儿?
Aus der Filnten.
And where does that get us?
如果他觉得我是朋友的话,
就会转移他的注意力.
It diverts his attention.
If he thinks I'm his friend...
那样的一个杂碎吗?
没有机会的.
A bastard like that?
No chance.
我们还想不想把那些孩子捞出来?
Do we want to get those kids
out of there or not?
会一切顺利的
It'll be fine.
1,2,3,4
One, two, three, four.
不!
Don't!
你觉得你在干嘛?
吵醒孩子们!
What do you think you're doing?
Waking little kids up!
380, 381, 382, 384.
385, 388, 387, 389.
向你祝贺,苏斯坎德.干得好.
谢谢你.
My compliments, Silskind. Well done.
Thank you.
用一个戴维的吻.
With a kiss from David.
我宁愿让他在身边.
快过他的生日了.
I'd rather keep him with me.
It's nearly his birthday.
他会被好好照顾的,
我承诺.
He'll be in good hands,
I promise you.
你明天没生过孩子.
You obviously don't have children.
格劳夫人...
Mrs Groenteman...
战后你们会团聚的.
他可以跟农夫们留在弗瑞兰.
You'll be reunited after the war.
He can stay with farmers in Friesland.
你的儿子如此.
我们年轻而健壮.
It's about your son.
We're young and strong.
非常有能力照顾好自己的孩子.
And quite capable of looking
after our own child.
甚至在集中营?
不行就是不行.
Even in a labour camp?
No is no.
继续干活,女士.
Just get on with your work, miss.
继续干活...
Just get on with your work...
你尽了全力.
You did your best.
但是那个孩子呢?
But what about that child?
安抚一下.
安抚？
Conciliate.
Conciliate?
费尔长官，他穿过了街道。
Aus der Filnten, he's across the street.
在CRAOCHE?
是的。
At the créche?
Yes.
他带着个婴儿。
He brought a baby.
我告诉你，这个地方仅为了犹太儿童。
I'm telling you, this place is only
for Jewish children.
从现在开始每个被遗弃的孩子都
当犹太人对待
From now on every abandoned child
is considered Jewish.
我愿意打赌保证她是犹太人。
I'm willing to bet you
she is Jewish.
苏斯坎德先生。
Mr Silskind.
昨天一切顺利。
向你祝贺。
That went well yesterday.
My compliments.
不可思议。
多么无情的母亲呀！
Incredible.
What an unnatural mother!
遗弃这么一个漂亮的婴儿。
Abandoning such a beautiful baby.
典型的犹太人行为。
Typical Jewish behaviour.
她看起来一点不像犹太人。
犹太人什么样？
She doesn't look Jewish at all.
What is Jewish?
鲍尔。
Bauer.
全都在这儿了。理论上说来。
It's all in here. Scientifically.
谁有皮尺吗？
Does anyone have a tape measure?
你忘了她的鼻子。
You forgot her nose.
百分百。
我知道。
One hundred percent.
I knew it.
她可以留下
She can stay.
或许一个喜剧结局的小块面包。
Perhaps a little toast
to a happy ending?
你为什么那样看着我？
Why are you looking at me like that?
很长时间没有跟同乡喝一杯了。
It's been a long time since I had
a drink with a fellow countryman.
那么，德国人在阿姆斯特丹干了什么？
So, what's a German
doing in Amsterdam?
我的祖父母来自荷兰。
我知道。
My grandparents were from Holland.
I see.
你想家吗？
Aren't you homesick?
谢谢
Thank you.
信不信由你，我23岁才吸烟喝酒。
NITA掉了！
Believe it or not, but until I was 23
I never smoked, never drank. Nita drop!
我们全都单纯善良。
We were all for nature,
for purity.
在松枝床上，睡在星空下
Sleeping under the stars
on a bed of pine needles.
有理想，有理性。
Dreaming and philosophizing.
我们想要改变世界。
We wanted to change the world.
我们也这么做了。
And we have done too.
我曾经有个同志。
I once had a comrade.
你不会再找到比他更好的了
You'd never find a better one.
战鼓敲响
The drum beat for battle.
他走过我身边。
He marched by my side.
我们保持步伐。
We kept in step.
保持步伐一致
一个子弹向我们射来。
A bullet flew towards us.
射向我还是射向他呢？
Is it for me or for him?
这带走了他的生命。
It took away his life.
现在，他就躺在我的脚下。
Now he's lying at my feet.
就像他倒向我。
As if he's pan' of me.
那些俄国人都是老虎。
德国佬没有把握时机。
Those Russians are tigers.
The Krauts don't stand a chance.
我想要去斯纳.
沃尔特？
I want to go to Sienna.
Walter?
去佛罗伦斯，去...！
And to Florence, the Ponce Vecchio!
战争还没结束.
The war's not over yet.
差不多了.不会太久.
It nearly is. Not long now.
我知道斯纳很好的酒店.
ll Fiore di Dante.
I know this really sweet hotel
in Sienna, ll Fiore di Dante.
他们有家乡风味的无花果酱.
They have homemade fig jam.
美味,但是亲爱的...
Delicious. But darling...
我不能离开.
I can't leave.
还不能.
Not yet.
是的,他们是为了你.
坚持住.像这样.
Yes, they're for you.
Hold on. Like this.
从这儿过.
Here you go.
通过
PASS
13张邮票.
我们做到了!我们做到了!
Thirteen stamps.
We did it! We did it!
你得呆在这儿.
不要被驱逐.
You have to stay here,
but won't be deported.
谢谢.
我会告诉豪普
Thank you.
I'll tell the Haupsturmï¬‚lhrer.
那是不可接受的.
做点什么吧.
That is unacceptable.
Do something about it.
鲁斯和西蒙沃特曼
谢谢上帝.
Roos and Simon Waterman,
thank God.
他们要去哪儿?
辛德勒彭.
Where will they go?
Hindeloopen.
嗨.
1,2,3,4,5
Hello.
One, two, three, four, five.
Coats.
快点
Hurry UP!
我们呆在这儿吗?
Are we staying here?
不,你稍后乘车.
和那个警察吗?
No, you'll take the train later.
With that cop?
稍等
Wait a minute
有问题吗?
ls there a problem?
那个小男孩不能来.很抱歉.
为什么?他回不来.
That little boy can't come. I'm sorry.
Why? He can't go back.
他得来.
但是他的卡片被破坏了.
He'll have to.
But his card's been destroyed.
没有人敢带着他
看他的脸
Nobody will dare take him.
Look at his face.
他的脸?
His face?
怎么回事?
这些人在拿生命冒险.
What's wrong with it?
These people are risking their lives.
我不会留下他独自一人
I'm not leaving him on his own!
现在是黑暗时期,年轻的女士.
These are dark days, young lady.
又是犹太人? 疯了!
Too Jewish? Meshuga!
也许是这样,如果他们检查的话
我们全都有巨大危险.
That may be so, but if they do
a check we're all in big trouble.
你想让他整天坐在那儿吗
You want him to sit in there all day?
我不认为那是个好主意.
I'm not sure that's a good idea.
上来这儿很棒.
那是他们看见的第一个地方.
Up here is perfect.
That's the first place they'll look.
荒谬.
但是真的.还会有别的.
It's absurd.
But it's true. And there will be more.
简直疯了!荒唐!
That's just crazy! Ridiculous!
小心你的手指!
Watch your fingers!
不，沃尔特。
No, Walter.
但是我们把他们放在哪儿？
他们无处可去，该死。
But where shall we put them?
There's nowhere they can go, dammit.
那边是什么？
What's over there?
一个学院
A college.
Mr. Van Hulst?
Miss Pimentel.
你们从礼堂(剧院)来，是不是？
苏斯坎德先生？
You're from the theatre, aren't you?
Mr Silskind?
是的，我想要问你件事。
Yes. I wanted to ask you something.
我知道你会有一天来看我，
并且不是通过前门。
I knew you'd come and see me one day.
And not via the front door.
你的屋棚。
Your shed.
我们能用一下吗？
Could we use it?
是急救，我拿走了？
It's an emergency, I take it?
半空的火车
A half-empty train.
你知道那要花多少钱吗？
Do you know how much that costs?
远远超出我的财力。
It is beyond my control.
你们有多少人？
大约400
How many people have you got here?
Almost 400.
几乎400
Almost 400?
很抱歉。
但是战争还要持续一阵子
'lam sorry, mein Fuhrer,
but the war will have to wait a while.
我尊敬的同事犯了个失误
My esteemed colleague
made a mistake.'
我不会魔术。
你也不会计数。
I can't do magic.
You can't count either.
400人就是400人
400 Jews are 400 Jews
不是什么几乎400
and not almost 400.
你们现在又多少孤儿？
没有父母，流落街道。
How many orphans do you have right now?
Without parents across the street.
几乎没有。
多少？
Hardly any.
How many?
连上她，13
那就够了
With her, thirteen.
That will just be enough.
拜托，他们只是孩子。
Please, they're just children.
犹太儿童，明天的敌人。
把他们包裹暖和。
Jewish children. Tomorrow's enemy
Wrap them up warm.
所有的13个
All thirteen?
继续走
And get a move on.
这远超我的财力。
相信我，我也不想这样
It's beyond my control.
Believe me, I don't want this either.
那么，不要这么做。
如果你不想。
Then don't do it
if you don't want to
我不得不，这是命令
做你能做的
I have to, it's an order.
Do what you can.
如果柏林命令式400，我只能发送
If Berlin orders 400
and I only send 387
你认为将会发生什么？
what do you think will happen?
对我？送到中央局？
To me? To the Central Bureau?
对她呢？
And to her?
德国战争工业要什么？
What does the German war industry want?
一个文明的国家不在工厂使用童工
A civilised country
doesn't make children work in factories.
家人相聚在一起
Families have to stay together.
数字不得不加总起来。
的确。
And the numbers have to add up.
Exactly.
Vigeveno, Lea.
Vigeveno, Isaac.
That's me.
De Vries, Salomon.
Yes, sir.
Flessedrager, Zwaantje.
我有个建议，苏斯坎德先生
I have a proposition, Mr Silskind.
你的选择，取决于你。
Your choice. It's up to you.
孩子们也不...
Either the children...
Of...
我的妈妈曾给科恩夫人做过清洁工
My mother worked as
a cleaning woman for Mrs Kohn.
她的丈夫是一个,你们怎么称呼呢,犹太教堂唱诗者
Her husband was a, what do you call it,
the singer in the synagogue?
Hazzan.
我得有七八岁了,当我听到科恩先生唱的时候
I must have been seven, eight years old
when I heard the Jew Kohn sing.
棒极了.
Wonderful!
我也想像那样唱
I wanted to sing like that too.
你有时候也那么觉得吗?
Do you feel that too sometimes...
忧伤使你高兴?
a sadness
that makes you happy?
你知道那种感觉吗?
Do you know that feeling?
是的
Yes.
他今天怎么样?
How is he today?
谁?
科恩先生?
Who?
Mr Kohn?
我们不是野蛮人
We're not barbarians.
多么美妙的管弦乐队啊
Such a beautiful orchestra.
或许我们应该送走孩子。
Maybe we should
send the children after all?
我会在周五小小庆祝一下
I'm having a little celebration
on Friday.
你出席我会很荣幸
I would value your presence.
我？
Me?
非常随意
就是我和几个朋友
It's very informal.
Just me and a few friends.
谢谢
Thank you.
为了邀请我
For inviting me.
但是，你看
But, you see...
我的妻子有一点焦虑
My wife is a little anxious.
能发生什么？
What can happen?
我也亲自保证你和你家人的安全
I personally guarantee your safety
and your family's too,
你也可以有个书面保证
you can have that in black and white.
好的，周五见
Well, see you this Friday then.
老科尔对你的朋友致以问候。
Old Cor sends his regards.
For your friend.
他让我恶心，杂碎
He makes me sick.
Bastard.
可也是自己人的杂碎
But our bastard.
自己人的？谁会去他的宴会？
Ours? Who's going
to his birthday party?
你是个英雄
我不要英雄，我想要个丈夫
You're a hero.
I don't want a hero, but a husband.
我们计划救走多少孩子？
5008个
How many have we managed to get away?
50, 80 children?
388人住。
338.
338 human lives.
卡车上我已经装了多少？
40000还是50000？
And how many have I put on the trucks?
40,000 or 50,000?
你不能那样想
You can't think like that.
我看见了全部的在黑暗中恐惧的脸
I see all those scared faces
in the dark.
好的。
OK, fine.
那么停止吧。但是不会再有孩子能逃脱了
So stop. But then no more children
will get away.
这取决于你。
It's up to you.
我想让你现在离开。
汉娜。
I'd like you to leave now.
Hanna.
或者我走。
Or I'll go.
去哪儿？
Where to?
Just bugger off!
There's an art to exaggerating.
Why would they?
犹太人的强制性劳力的结果是种族灭绝
"The forced labour of the Jews turns out
to be systematic extermination."
英式的宣传。
我希望你是对的
English propaganda.
I hope you're right.
5星。谢谢
Five stars. Thank you.
多谢。亲爱的沃尔特
Many thanks, dear... Walter.
我可以称呼你沃尔特吗？
当然。
May I call you Walter?
Of course.
你和我在同一条船上。
你不知道，是不是？
You and I are in the same boat.
You didn't know that, did you?
当这个结束，当这个地方清除了犹太人，
我们都可以去东部
When this is over, when the place is
cleansed of Jews, we can both go east.
你去波兰工作
我去俄国前线
You to work in Poland,
me to the Front in Russia.
我可以问你些那种情况吗？
你知道那意味着什么吗？
May I ask you something about that?
Do you know what that means?
去东部前线？
不。
The Eastern Front?
No.
你除了...什么都不是.
You're nothing but cannon fodder.
直到你被吹成碎片.
Until you're blown to pieces.
对不起,沃尔特.
Sorry, Walter.
这个时候一切太过分了点.
It's all a bit much at the moment.
在我生日时,
And on my birthday, of all days...
I got a river front my sister.
你有兄弟吗?
是的.
Do you have any brothers?
Yes.
我再也没有了
I don't any more.
周日
Sunday...
海姆特自杀了.
Helmut hanged himself.
上帝
God!
这儿.
不.谢谢.我好了.
Here.
No. Thank you. I'm alright.
这该死的战争.
This damned war!
如果不是为了战争,
我们也许会是很好的朋友.
If it weren't for the war,
we might very well be friends.
是的.
真正的好朋友.
Yes.
Really good friends.
欢迎.
Welcome.
晚上好,西奇夫人.
Good evening, Mrs Hirschfeld.
来打猎野鸡有趣吧?
野鸡到处都是
Fancy coming pheasant hunting?
They're everywhere.
阿尔伯特!
佛迪。身日快乐。
Albert!
Ferdi. Happy birthday.
谢谢。
Thanks.
我听说了你兄弟的事情。
你的妹妹一定很抓狂。
I heard about your brother.
Your sister must be very upset.
是的
Yes.
战争就是战争。
美酒就是美酒。
War is war.
And a drink is a drink.
别担心，我们不会送你去沃戈。
Don't worry. They won't
be sending you to the Volga!
干杯。
Cheers.
只要全欧洲的事情进行的向这里
的同样顺利。
If only it was going as smoothly
all over Europe as here.
来观看很荣幸。
谢谢我们的礼堂(剧院)主管。
It's a pleasure to watch.
Thanks to our theatre manager.
苏斯坎德先生，
Mr Silskind, Obersturmï¬‚lhrer Gemmeker.
西波克过度营的长官。
Commandant of
Westerbork Transition Camp.
见到你很高兴。
见到你很高兴。请原谅。
Pleased to meet you.
Pleased to meet you. Excuse me.
为你的妻子。
For your wife.
谢谢。
Thank you.
希尔维？
Sylvie?
只是给你的！
And this is for you!
开心点。沃尔特。
Have fun, Walter.
L...
希尔维，你应该知道...
你很羞涩,是不是?
Sylvie, you should know...
You are shy, aren't you?
一个大人物
A high-up...
但不是党卫军,对吗?
but not SS, right?
完全不是.
Not really.
但是你是德国人.
But you are German.
一个可爱的,羞涩的德国佬.
A sweet, shy Kraut.
一个饥渴的德国佬?
A horny Kraut?
拜托,不要那样做.
Please, don't do that.
是的.非常高的级别!
Yes, very high UP!
我结婚了,希尔维.
I'm married, Sylvie.
是吗.我也是.
我不会让你筋疲力竭,你知道。
Are you? So am I.
I won't wear you out, you know.
你很有胆量.我一生中见多了疯狂
的事情.
You have guts. I've seen
some meshuga things in my time...
那就是我不跟党卫军的原因.
That's why I'm not with the SS.
别担心，宝贝。
我不会埋掉你。
Don't worry, sweetie.
I'm not going to grass on you.
包括这里所有的女孩们。
All the girls here are.
西奇夫人。
And Mrs Hirschfeld. Madame.
作为一个Sperre证的交换。
似乎使得俄国佬变得特别饥渴.
In exchange for a Sperre.
Seems to make the Krauts extra horny.
现在，我们要不要做点什么？
Now, are we going
to do anything or not?
不要。
Don't then.
那么，你为什么来这儿？
So why did you come here?
打从我们文雅的绅士们那儿？
From our civilised gentleman?
像个老鼠一样的悬挂着。
Hung like a mouse.
“敬启者”
'To whom it may concern.
"沃尔特苏斯坎德已经成为了
第三德国忠实的仆人。"
Walter Suskind has always been
a loyal servant of the Third Reich.'.
好的。好的。
Well, well.
"他支持党卫军，听从责任感的召唤。"
'Who has supported the SS
above and beyond the call of duty.'.
Period.
"他和他的家人均不会有任何方式的抵抗"
'Neither he nor his family
should be impeded in anyway.'.
Period.
"佛迪南签名，SIPO和SD的长官"
'Signed Ferdinand Aus der Filnten,
Commander of the SiPo and the SD.'.
天哪！你是他的流落的儿子吗？
他的什么？
Bloody hell! Are you his bum boy?
His what?
叛徒！从我这儿滚开！
Traitor! Get the hell away from me!
为了个Sperre证去拍马屁吧。
Licking that scum's arse for a Sperre.
那么你呢？纳粹的贱人。
是的。正确。
And you then? Nazi whore.
Yeah, right.
否则，我现在就坐在云上了。
Otherwise I'd be sitting
on a cloud now.
就像我的奶奶，父母，姐姐，侄女儿们
Just like my grandma, parents,
sister, nieces...
整条街，被带走了。
The whole street, taken away.
他们会在战后回来。
你以为吗？
They'll come home after the war.
You think?
你应该在你的德国佬朋友
小便的时候听说过。
You should hear your Kraut friends
when they're pissed.
你以为呢？
他们永远回不来了。
What are you on about?
They're never coming back.
他们不得不做工。
是吗？全裸着？
They only have to work.
Oh yeah? Completely naked?
男人和女人，
妈妈带着他们的孩子？
Men and women,
mothers with their children?
他们让你脱衣服，然后...
They make you take your clothes off.
And then...
然后什么?
Then what?
沐浴.他们说.
In the shower. They say.
却没有水流出来
Except no water comes out.
然后什么?
What then?
什么流出来?
What comes out?
然后什么流出来?
What comes out then?
毒气
Gas.
你也是.
You too.
你,很容易.是的.
You, just as easily. Yes.
你不相信我,是不是?
我应该相信什么?
You don't believe me, do you?
What should I believe?
救生艇不存在.
汉娜,你要死了.
The lifeboat doesn't exist.
Hanna, you're going to die.
停止.你用MAFIER干嘛?
Stop it! What's the mafier with you?
我打算用.送他们走向死亡.
我们就是一大堆垃圾.
I disposed of them. Sent them to their
death. We're just a big heap of offal.
你,我和伊冯.
不!
You, me and Yvonne.
No!
你不相信我，是不是？
You don't believe me, do you?
看着我。
Look at me.
Look at me!
看着我，你看什么呢？
Look at me.
What do you see?
你看什么呢？
一个酸菜佬。
A Kraut.
你他妈的酸菜佬。
You're a fucking Kraut.
我死也不干！
I won't bloody do it.
送走人们是一件事。
Sending people away is one thing.
但是作为屠杀的同谋呢？
你忘了这一点。
But an accessory to murder?
You forgot that bit.
苏斯坎德先生。
你是什么意思？
Mr Silskind.
What do you mean?
希特勒在兑现他的承诺。
波兰很厉害，是的
Hitler is doing what he promised!
Poland is tough, yes.
饥荒和瘟疫并行，
人们不得不努力干活。
There's hunger, people have to work
very hard, there are diseases.
别胡扯了！
他们被杀害了。
Don't bullshit me!
They're being murdered.
被歼灭，屠杀，像蝼蚁一样
Annihilated,
exterminated like... vermin.
请你停止行吗？
Will you stop, please?
又是那个毒气卡车的恐怖故事吗？
That horror story
about gas trucks again?
你从那儿得来的消息？
Where did you get that from?
从一个为党卫军工作的人那儿。
一个犹太女人。
From someone who works
for the SS. A Jewess.
她为党卫军工作？
一个妓女，通敌者。
Who works for the SS?
A tart! Horizontal collaboration.
胡扯！
Bullshit!
我听说了。在公园里。
由尤拉经营的妓院。
I've heard of it. By the park.
The brothel run by Ulla Hirschfeld.
即便她说的是真的，
你想让我们怎么做？
Even if what she says is true,
what would you have us do?
我们能怎么做？
停止，就是停止！
What can we do?
Stop, just stop!
把礼堂(剧院)留给纳粹？
Leave the theatre to the Nazis?
做点事情。让人们知道！
Do something. Let people know!
我不想在礼堂(剧院)里爆发恐慌。
I wouldn't want panic
to break out in the theatre.
荷兰还剩下多少？
40000还是50000？
How many are left in Holland?
40 or50,000?
他们全部将被毒杀。
你想让他们怎么办？
They're all going to be gassed.
What do you want them to do?
我怎么知道？藏起来！做点什么。
How do I know? Go into hiding!
Do something.
那是被禁止的。
That's forbidden.
禁止!去他的！
他们要灭族！
Forbidden? Goddammit!
They're wiping us out!
藏匿的人群对我们的社会是个危险
People in hiding
are a danger to our community.
这必然导致复仇。
It inevitably leads to reprisals.
照顾好人民是我们的责任。
It is our duty
to take care of our people.
解决温饱，医疗，减轻创痛。
Feed them, give them
medical assistance, alleviate the pain.
我们不可能，也做不了，更多的事。
We cannot, may not, do more.
我不能，你不能。
Not I, not you.
真是个人道主义者。
A true Humanist.
科恩先生战前不是个教授吗？
Wasn't Mr Cohen
a professor before the war?
古文学科的。
世界上，我仍旧如是。
Of Classics.
I still am, actually.
你是个为纳粹工作的从业者。
那是你。我请辞。
You're an undertaken for the Nazi's.
That's what you are. I quit.
我能给你个忠告吗?
继续下去吗？
Can I give you a word of advice?
Just carry on?
恩。
自己干。
Yes.
Do it yourself.
你已经有了联络渠道。
You've got the contacts.
你认为我为什么给你这个工作？
Why did you think I gave you the job?
因为你的钢琴表演艺术吗？
Because of your virtuoso piano playing?
那么你...
So you...
你怎么能知道我...
你这么勇敢?我不知道.
How could you know that I'd...
That you were so brave? I didn't.
但是你不得不继续下去。
But you have to carry on.
我们命该如此。所有人。
We're doomed anyway. All of us.
炸弹掉在了每个人的头上。
Just bomb the shit out of it all.
礼堂(剧院)，铁路。
The theatre, the railway.
西波克，奥斯奇。
Westerbork, Auschwitz.
他们为什么？
A few bombs and it's done with.
Why would they?
该死的英国人。
Damn English.
所有的一切为了赢得战争。
It's all about winning the war.
我为什么要关心谁书谁赢呢？
如果我不在那儿也看不见？
Why should I care who wins the war
if I won't be there to see it?
我不认目睹他们。我说不出话。
I can't stand the sight of them,
I can't breathe language.
该死的德国佬。
Damn Krauts.
我们能找到他吗？
Shall we get him?
他们怎么来这儿？
How did they get here?
妈妈不会让我跟着她的。
毛裴也不会。
Mummy wouldn't let me go with her.
Maupie neither.
我要把你放那儿呢，孩子？
Where am I going to put you, child?
过来。
Come on.
没问题，人人需要孩子。
毛裴。
No problem. Everybody wants babies.
Maupie.
真可爱。但递交给女孩们。
Cute. But please leave
the deliveries to the girls.
一个带孩子的男人太可疑了。
但是我们在酒吧见面。
A man with a baby is suspicious.
But we meet in a bar.
这儿？他们是共产党。每个人都是。
Here? They're Communists,
every one of them.
毛裴也有一个姐姐。
9岁大，莫扎。
Maupie's got a sister too.
Nine years old, Mirjam.
好的。但是不太犹太化。
没人要他们。
Fine, but nothing too Jewish.
No-one wants them.
那么我把这女孩放哪儿呢？
棚里满了。
Where do I put the girl then?
The shed is full.
这有一个蓝眼睛的孩子么？
Isn't there one with blue eyes?
看上去不太犹太。
那么她就能跟我走。
Just less obviously Jewish.
Then she can come with me.
不太犹太？
Less Jewish?
来吧。小姑娘，坐这儿。
Come on, little girl, sit here.
快点
Hurry UP...
抓牢了。我们走了。
Hold on tight. Here we go.
鲁斯！
Roos!
鲁斯！鲁斯！
Roos! Roos!
Henneicke Column.
Henneicke Column?
从没听说过。
你想跟我说话吗？
Never heard of it.
You wanted to speak to me?
不。只是需要你在交接单上签名。
No. Just need you to sign for delivery.
什么？
她藏起来了。在伦特恩。
Of what?
She was in hiding. In Lunteren.
如果我不签名呢？
And what if I don't sign?
那我就拿不到工钱了。
值7块五
Then I don't get my money, you sod.
That's worth seven-fifty!
酬劳？抱歉。没门
A reward? Sorry, no chance.
那么我带她去SD。没问题。她属于这儿
Then I'll take her to the SD.
Out of the question. She belongs here.
现在听我说，仔细点，我的朋友。
Now listen to me
very carefully, my friend.
我让你干你的活，
所以你也让我干活。
I let you do your bloody work
so let me do mine.
你称之为干活？
不。
You call this work?
No.
我的干劲儿。我的活是清空地方，发送货物去柏林拍卖。
My passion. My work is emptying houses
Sending stuff to Berlin for auction.
犹太人这样的货物
Jews' stuff.
挣犹太人的钱？
And the money from the 'Jews' stuff?
别抱怨了。过去当然都是坐车花钱的。
Stop whining. It's used to pay
for the trains, of course.
为了他们自己的运输业花钱。
They pay for their own transport.
呆在这儿！让我走！
Stay here! Let go of me!
开枪！开枪！
Shoot then! Shoot!
你在等什么?
需要我指给你吗？
What are you waiting for?
Need me to show you how?
让我躲开枪。
Let go of my gun!
出去这条路。
Out the way.
他们接下来再藏哪儿？
Where will they hide next?
疼吗？
只在我笑得时候。
Does it hurt?
Only when I laugh.
芬妮怎么办？
What will happen to Fanny?
如果她说出来怎么办？
What if she talks?
说点什么吧，沃尔特。
他们来了怎么办？
Say something, Walter.
What if they come here?
不会的。你不认识她。
你也不认得盖斯特普
Won't happen. You don't know her.
And you don't know the Gestapo.
别傻了。
你是个叛徒。好好想想吧。
Don't be so stupid!
You're a traitor, think about it.
你已经是费尔长官同一条船了
You've taken Aus der Filnten for a ride.
真可怕，是不是？
Terrible, isn't it?
你已经做的足够了。你不是上帝。
救世主沃尔特。
You've done enough, you're not God!
Walter the Messiah.
我们去度假。
我们得藏起来。现在！
We'll go on holiday.
We're going into hiding. Now!
他们会逮捕大家。皮耶特，费列克斯
They'll arrest everyone. Piet, Felix...
又来了，救世主沃尔特！
我们得走了。
There, Walter the Messiah again!
We have to leave.
我们搞到了那些石头。
We've got those stones.
有芬妮的消息吗？
Any news of Fanny?
她在明天的四点半火车上。
该死！
She's on the half-four train tomorrow.
Dammit!
她跟他们说出什么了吗？
那么他们已经埋伏在那儿了。
Did she tell them anything?
Then they'd already be here.
我们怎么把她弄下来。
How can we get her off there?
中央局分局
Pinched from the Central Bureau.
一个逮捕证明。
An arrest warrant.
谁逮捕谁。
你逮捕芬妮。
And who will arrest who?
You, Fanny.
他们什么理由下来？
一点骗术，一点演技。
And they'll fall for that?
A bit of bluffing, play-acting.
你是剧院的经理，不是吗？
You are a theatre manager,
aren't you?
明天见。
See you tomorrow.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
我要离开，和伊冯一起。
I'm leaving. With Yvonne!
我们还来得及跑掉。
We can still get away.
那么帮助我。
Help me then!
在你知道以前，T军和红军就会来这里
并且你...
Before you know it, the Tommies
and the Reds will be here and you...
还在抽雪茄吗?
和那个老乡.
will still be smoking cigars
with that clown.
他是不可或缺的。
He is indispensable.
For the saboteurs, yes.
她在独自表演。她说她会尽力带
她的侄子逃走。
She was acting alone. She said she was
trying to get her nephew away.
她在明天的火车上。
跟你一样。
She's on tomorrow's train.
As will you be.
一张去高加索的单程票。
A one-way ticket to the Caucasus.
我不干。我们在这儿的工作
一个月后就结束了。清除犹太人。
I wouldn't do that. Our work here'll be
finished in a month. Cleansed of Jews.
多亏我和这个老乡
Thanks to me and to this clown.
他会让你包裹起你的手。
我会拷问他。
He's got you wrapped round his finger.
I'll give him a good grilling.
真的？不要忘了带上你的天鹅绒手套
Really? Don't forget to
wear your velvet gloves.
苏斯坎德不会出卖我的。
Silskind wouldn't betray me.
盖斯特普保监令
GESTAPO
PROTECTIVE CUSTODY ORDER
太棒了。事情应该成了。
Brilliant. That should do it.
我们期望如此吧。
Let's hope so.
菲利普...
Philips...
菲利普,芬妮.把她留在那儿.
Philips, Fanny. Leave her on there.
只是中央局来的.
名单上的就是名单上的.
This is from the Central Bureau.
On the list is on the list.
命令就是命令.
西波克.
An order's an order.
Westerbork.
不,不是西波克.
毛斯,马上.
No, not Westerbork.
Mauthausen, right away.
叛徒.
她是个罪人
The traitor.
She's a criminal.
跟你一样.上车.
或者你需要帮助吗?
As are you! Get on the train.
Or do you need help?
兹莫...
我在名单上吗?
Zimmermann...
Am I on that list?
我不在乎.你也可以走了.
你知道谁划的名单吗?我!
I don't care. You can go too.
D'you know who draws the lists up? Me!
我做的!
然后我将亲自加上你的名字.
I do!
Then I will personally add your name.
是什么?
苏斯坎德.
What is it?
Silskind.
和你的,霍尔?
And yours, Herr Rottenï¬‚lhrer?
斯查
Scharï¬‚lhrer Schiinfeld.
现在上车.斯查.
Now get on the train.
Scharï¬‚lhrer Schiinfeld.
如果你一定要就把我放上车吧.
Put me on the train if you must.
但我能确保你会乘上下一班.
But I can assure you that
you will be on the next one.
并且车不会在西波克停.
And it won't stop at Westerbork.
停下火车!
Stop the train!
谢谢.
Thank you.
向你祝贺.
做的好.做的很好.
My compliments.
Well done. Very well done.
什么事这么紧急?
What was so urgent?
你的朋友
Your friend.
在2天的时间里,他想要一半的白袖章
In two days' time
he wants half of all the white armbands,
7000人,被驱逐.
7,000 people, to be deported.
他们很迅速.
阿姆斯特丹已经肃清了犹太人.
They're in a hurry.
Amsterdam has been cleansed of Jews.
如果不剩犹太人了还要
犹太理事会干嘛?
Why have a Jewish Council
if there are no Jews left?
当然,科恩顽劣的抵抗?
科恩跟他们花了一上午.
Cohen protested fiercely, of course?
Cohen spent the morning with them
想法从名单上废除30个名字
and managed to get thirty names
scrapped from the list.
那30个明天就能得到豁免信.
Those thirty will get
an exemption letter tomorrow
告诉他们不必报告。
telling them they don't have to report.
艾斯和肯恩签署。
Signed by Asscher and Cohen.
你意思是我能不能够制作7000多的信件?
为什么？那么做有什么好处？
You mean can I make 7,000 more letters?
Why? What good will that do them?
那会给他们一点转寰的时间。
获得自由的一线希望。
It'd give them a little extra time.
A glimpse of freedom.
幻觉式的抉择。
The illusion of a choice.
我们现在有多少了？
超过6000.
How many have we got now?
Over 6,000.
这个把戏可能以他的脑袋为代价。
谁的？
This trick could cost him his head.
Who?
我们的豪普。
Our Hauptsturmï¬‚lhrer.
复仇很酷。
Revenge is sweet.
我不真的想复仇。
但他也许想。
I don't really want revenge.
But he might.
Achtung!
苏斯坎德？苏斯坎德？
我的犹太人呢？
Silskind? Silskind?
Where are my Jews?
你，起来！
You, get up!
苏斯坎德在哪儿？
Where is Silskind?
我在问你！
I asked you a question!
让他们滚开，全部！
Get them out of here. All of them!
是的，长官！出去，大家出去！
Yes, sir! Get out, everybody out!
出去，我说。
Out, I said.
你聋了吗？出去！
Are you deaf? Out!
那是我说的。
That's what I'm saying.
听着，科恩先生。我可以向你保证。
这对我也是个秘密。
Listen, Mr Cohen. I can assure you,
it's a mystery to me too.
稍等。
Just a moment.
上帝。
My God.
带两个人把全部人赶出去。
Take two men and
get them all out of there.
是的，长官！
你跟我去，你也去。
Yes, sir!
You, come with me. You too.
我其余的7000犹太人在哪儿？
Where's the rest of my 7,000 Jews?
我在等他们。
I'm waiting for them.
时间还早。
It's still early.
跪下！
On your knees!
手放背后。
Hands behind your back.
手举过头
Hands behind your head.
如果我扣动扳机会发生什么？
What will happen
if I pull the trigger now?
那么我就完了。
Then I'll be gone.
我是说，冲着我的话。
I mean, to me.
你认为我会哀悼你的死吗？
Do you think I will mourn your death?
是的，我认为我会想念你。
Yes, I think I would miss you.
你不必要开枪。
You don't have to shoot.
不，我知道。我自己有一个愿望。
No, I know. I have a will of my own.
我可以选在不开枪。
I can choose not to shoot.
也或许无论如何都会毙了你。
Or maybe I'll shoot you anyway.
如果你杀了我。
If you kill me
你真的认为那七千人会出现吗
do you really think
those 7,000 will turn up?
该死的！
我会为此掉脑袋！
Dammit!
They'll have my head for this!
你没有做错什么。
这超出了你的控制。
You didn't do anything wrong.
It's beyond your control.
告诉斯特
Tell Sturmbannï¬‚lhrer Lages that.
有人欺骗了我们，背叛了我们。
Someone deceived us. Betrayed us.
继续，走。
容易，容易。
Go on. Move.
Easy, easy.
快点
Faster!
不！
No!
Aaron!
上来！
呆在你的地方。
Up there!
Stay where you are!
再快点。
Faster!
希尔维？
Sylvie?
继续。
Go on.
来吧。
我们要去哪儿？
Come on.
Where are we going?
安静点，恩？
Quietly, eh?
集中精力。
下一个。过来。
Mind your head.
Next one. Come on.
我早上会多带点来。
I'll bring some more in the morning.
去睡觉。
Go to sleep.
晚安。
Goodnight.
你们的老乡现在能随心所欲的
腊印很多信。
That clown of yours can now stencil
as many letters as he likes.
苏斯坎德？
Silskind?
这不是真的。
你是个二百五，豪普。
It's not true.
You're a half-wit, Hauptsturmï¬‚lhrer.
一个懦夫。
A wimp.
嗨。打开门!
Hello! Open the door!
打开。
Open up.
打开，警察。
Open Hp, police.
过来，让我们去楼上看一下。
Come on, let's take a look upstairs.
他们走了。
They've gone.
他们不在这儿。
They're not here.
那很危险。
你应该来里面。
That's dangerous.
You should come inside.
请原谅
Excuse me.
对不起，请原谅。
Sorry. Excuse me.
沃尔特。
希尔维？
Walter.
Sylvie?
今天上午他们把所有人装走了。
所有的女孩，每个人。
They picked them all up this morning.
All the girls. Everybody.
哦，不，孩子们呢？
Oh no, and the children?
他们还在那儿。
They're still there.
他们都听见我们了。
我打不开。
They'll hear us.
I can't open it.
我不能让他们挨饿。
我不得不回去。
I can't let them starve.
I have to go back.
回去？
Back?
你回不去的。
You can't go back.
我不得不去
I have to.
我认识能帮你的某个人。
I know someone who can help me.
这让我烦透了。
This makes me sick.
那些女孩怎么办呢？
What about these girls?
你会怎么抉择呢：
跳舞还是波兰？
What would you choose:
dancing or Poland?
我们的犹太人党委军
Our Jewish SS.
回来。
Get back.
干得好。现在你不会被驱逐了。
我说。回来。
Well done. Now you won't be deported.
I said, get back.
奥伯斯！
Obersturmï¬‚lhrer!
司令认识我。
The Commandant knows me.
I don't give a shit!
司令！
Commandant!
我没以前见过面。
对不起，但是现在很忙。
We've met before.
Sorry, but it's urgent.
对。
Right.
我是礼堂(剧院)的经理。
I'm the theatre manager.
豪普，在费尔长官的生日上。
Hauptsturmﬂlhrer Aus der Fifteen’s
birthday?
我不记得了。
在阿姆斯特丹。在霍斯夫人家。
I don't remember.
In Amsterdam. At Mrs Hirschfeld's.
没听说过。带他走开。
Never heard of it. Take him away.
不。
No.
跟我来。
Come with me.
停下！
Stop!
够了。
Enough!
你是苏斯坎德，是不是？
You're Silskind, aren't you?
是的。
Yes.
有个人想跟你讲话。
There's someone
who wants to talk to you.
By the latrines.
OK.
上帝保佑你。
God bless you.
不要问我任何问题。
Don't ask any questions.
我亲爱的。
My darling.
我不会离开你。
I'll never leave you.
亲爱的。
Sweetheart.
伊冯子在哪儿？
Where's Yvonne?
她睡了。
She's asleep.
他...
不要问任何问题.
Did he...
Don't ask any questions.
我们会永远在一起的.
We'll always be together.
永远.
Forever.
听着,沃尔特.
Listen, Walter.
明天...
Tomorrow...
你可以去阿姆斯特丹.
You can go to Amsterdam.
在早上.
In the morning.
没问题.
No questions.
他想要奶奶的石头.
他明天午夜给你.
He wants Grandma's stones.
He'll give you till midnight tomorrow.
你呢?
And you?
我要呆在这儿.
I'm staying here.
但是你得走.
But you have to go.
那些孩子...
Those children...
我亲爱的.
My darling.
是的.
Yes.
你要在午夜回来.带着奶奶的宝石.
You will be back by midnight.
With Grandma's treasure.
如果你欺骗了我.他们就会在下一班
火车上.
If you try to cheat me,
they'll be on the very next train.
如果我不是故意欺骗你呢?
那么她就还是你的.
And if I don't try to cheat you?
Then she is yours once more.
你的和你自己的
Yours and yours alone.
别担心.
她在下一个告示之前有一个SPERRE证.
Don't worry.
She has a Sperre until further notice.
你说话算数吗?
Do I have your word?
算数.
You have my word
沃尔特.
Walter.
沃尔特叔叔.
Uncle Walter!
天黑前我会回来.
I'll be back before dark.
你认为我也能洗个澡吗?
Do you think I can take a bath too?
你要你保持安静.
As long as you keep them quiet.
还有呢?
And?
他们很安全.
They're safe.
我们不得不就他们出去.
快.
We have to get them out of there.
And quick.
PISS OFF!
对14个孩子来说那足够吗?
Is that enough for 14 children?
足够了.
其余是给杰米的.
Plenty.
The rest are for Gemmeker.
什么?
没什么.
What?
Nothing.
我们应该迅速.
We should hurry.
你.
You.
关键人物!
The key man!
莎莉!莎莉在哪儿?
Sallie! Where is Sallie?
莎莉
Sallie?
西蒙,来吧.快点!
Simon, come on, hurry up!
关上!
Close it! Close it!
小犹太崽子!你还活着吗?
Bloody little Jew! Are you still alive?
Let go of me!
我们这儿有什么?
What have we here?
2,4,6,8,10
Two, four, six, eight, ten.
那会带来个好数值.
That'll bring in a nice amount.
沃尔特
Walter!
事情会好的.另一列车在九点一刻发
It'll be alright. Another train
leaves at quarter past nine.
你所有要做的是逃走.
逃走?
Everything you need to get away.
Get away?
你得秘密离开,沃尔特.
把汉娜留在后边?
You have to go underground, Walter.
And leave Hanna behind?
今晚一个小艇离开.我会带你去科特.
A boat leaves tonight.
I'll take you to Katwijk.
去科特?我需要去西波克.
我跟杰米留话了.
To Katwijk? I need to go to Westerbork
I gave Gemmeker my word.
他也给你留话了吗?
是的.
And he gave you his?
Yes.
他找到了宝石,汉娜得到了一个
有效期到下一个通知的SPERRE证.
He gets the diamonds, Hanna gets
a Sperre until further orders.
好的,似乎命令已经下了.
Well, it seems the order has been given.
谁下的?
By Who?
谁下的?为什么?
我不知道，他们在名单上。
By who? Why?
I don't know, but they're on the list.
今晚。
Tonight.
一点半有一次驱逐。
There's a deportation at half past one.
再见，孩子。
Bye, kids.
亲爱的。
Sweetie.
再见。
Bye.
沃尔特叔叔？
Uncle Walter?
嗨，小不点儿。
我勇敢的孩子。
Hi, little one.
My brave boy.
一路顺风。
Have a good trip.
我能跟你一起吗？
不。
Can I come with you?
No.
那么你要去哪儿？
Where are you going then?
我不知道。
I don't know.
最终的结局是胜利！
AT THE END IS VICTORY!
妈咪！
Mummy!
Easy, here. Easy!
我的事，我照料好我的事。
你的事是呆在这儿。
My case. I'm looking for my case.
Your case is staying here.
请原谅。
继续走，继续。
Excuse me.
Move along. Go on.
司令在哪儿？
Where's the Commandant?
Go on. Move along!
Hanna?
拜托，我生病了。
Please, I'm ill.
该死的杂碎!
Bloody bastard!
让我走。
Let go of me!
狗娘养的，学习点教养！
他也是个人。
Son of a bitch, learn some discipline!
He's a human being too!
妈妈，妈妈在哪儿？
Mum, where is Mum?
苏斯坎德先生？跟我来。
Mr Silskind? Follow me.
我的妻子，她在哪儿？
My wife, where is she?
我的孩子呢？
And my child?
杰米先生，我们做个交易。
Mr Gemmeker, we had a deal.
我们同意...
我知道,苏斯坎德先生.
We agreed...
I know, Mr Silskind.
这远远超出了我的控制.
It was beyond my control.
汉娜在哪儿.
Where is Hanna?
我的妻子和孩子
My wife and my child
汉娜!
Hanna!
一个人也可能是就个失误。
A person can be mistaken.
我认为我们是朋友。
I thought we were friends.
你...?
Did you...?
你把汉娜...?
游戏结束了.
Did you have Hanna...?
The game is over.
拜托,佛迪南
Please, Ferdinand.
请求你...
Please...
汉娜和伊冯.苏斯坎德.
Hanna and Yvonne Silskind.
14车厢
Carriage number 14.
该死的德国佬.
Bloody Kraut!
汉娜和伊冯被毒杀于1944年10月24日
HANNA AND YVONNE WERE GASSED
IN AUSCHWITZ ON 24 OCTOBER 1944.
沃尔特约4个月后死亡。
WALTER PROBABLY DIED
FOUR MONTHS LATER
于欧洲中部的某个死亡营地。
ON ONE OF THE DEATH MARCHES
SOMEWHERE IN CENTRAL EUROPE.
在这一年期间，他经营着荷兰剧院
DURING THE YEAR HE WAS IN CHARGE
OF THE DUTCH THEATRE,
沃尔特苏斯坎德救助了超过一千
人的生命。
WALTER SUSKIND HELPED SAVE THE
LIVES OF OVER A THOUSAND PEOPLE.
鲁斯！
Roos!
西蒙！
Simon!
此片献给所有至今仍在遭受侮辱
和迫害的人们。
DEDICATED TO ALL THOSE STILL BEING
HUMILIATED AND PERSECUTED TODAY.
从礼堂(剧院)走出的获救的孩子们
在自由中被抚养成人。
THE CHILDREN FROM THE THEATRE
WERE SAVED AND GREW UP IN FREEDOM.
成千上万的儿童仍然深陷战争
的恐怖深渊。
MILLIONS OF CHILDREN ARE STILL
CAUGHT UP IN THE HORRORS OF WAR.
WAR CHILD在帮助这样的儿童。
我们声援该慈善组织。
WAR CHILD HELPS THESE CHILDREN.
WE SUPPORT THIS CHARITY.